<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on The ERC Blog</title>
    <link>https://erc-bpgc.github.io/blog/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on The ERC Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://erc-bpgc.github.io/blog/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Robotic Arms: A Brief</title>
      <link>https://erc-bpgc.github.io/blog/blog/robotic_arms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://erc-bpgc.github.io/blog/blog/robotic_arms/</guid>
      <description>Most of the world&amp;rsquo;s robots are designed for hard, repetitive production work. They perform activities that human beings find complicated, dangerous or tedious. The most common production robot is a robotic arm.
A robotic arm is a device that is programmed to carry out a particular task with extreme accuracy at a rapid pace with great efficiency.
History of the arm The idea of a robot arm is not new. The first robotic arm was designed by Leonardo da Vinci in the late fifteenth century.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modular Self Reconfigurable Robots</title>
      <link>https://erc-bpgc.github.io/blog/blog/mssr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://erc-bpgc.github.io/blog/blog/mssr/</guid>
      <description>Robots were invented with the goal of helping humans carry out their tasks more comfortably, particularly 4D (Dirty, Dangerous, Difficult, and Dull) tasks. In designing robots, the conventional approach has been to design their hardware and software in accordance with the tasks they are supposed to do. Conventional robots can perform specific tasks accurately, but they are not very versatile and adaptive, and thus applications that are consigned to them rely heavily on their physical structure and controller capabilities.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
