<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>automation on The ERC Blog</title>
    <link>https://erc-bpgc.github.io/blog/categories/automation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in automation on The ERC Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://erc-bpgc.github.io/blog/categories/automation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Behaviour Based Robotics</title>
      <link>https://erc-bpgc.github.io/blog/blog/bbr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://erc-bpgc.github.io/blog/blog/bbr/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever wondered why we humans survived the race of evolution amongst all the other creatures that inhabited Earth millions of years ago?
It is because of our intelligence and ability to acclimatize to a changing environment. Similarly, the idea of robots operating in response to their environment was proposed in the late eighties. This was known as Behavior-Oriented Artificial Intelligence.
In that era, robots were designed to do labor-intensive tasks and the term artificial intelligence was limited to robots executing specific sets of instructions on their own which were already fed to their system at the time of design which was previously known as ‘classical AI’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Model Predictive Control</title>
      <link>https://erc-bpgc.github.io/blog/blog/model_predictive_control/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://erc-bpgc.github.io/blog/blog/model_predictive_control/</guid>
      <description>The below animation depicts a Model Predictive Control on a dynamic four-legged robot by Yanran Ding.
 RF-MPC on a Qadruped
  Over the years, the advancement in robotics and related areas has allowed robot models to have complex and non-linear dynamic equations. The application of such robots involves dynamic environments or environments which are highly inaccessible to humans. Such robot models introduced new challenges in the control strategies as typical industrial controllers such as PID controllers can fail in guaranteeing many features in these areas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heuristically guided Sampling based Path Planning</title>
      <link>https://erc-bpgc.github.io/blog/blog/heuristically_guided_sampling_based_path_planning/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://erc-bpgc.github.io/blog/blog/heuristically_guided_sampling_based_path_planning/</guid>
      <description>One of the easiest tasks for us humans to do is move from one place to another without even meticulously planning our way. We get up from our seats and walk to the cafe, get our drink and come back to our seats. During this entire “action” that we performed, we hardly give any thought about the “trajectory” that we have to follow. For example, while walking or running, when we see that there is a banana peel or a pothole in our “path”, we tend to avoid it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modular Self Reconfigurable Robots</title>
      <link>https://erc-bpgc.github.io/blog/blog/mssr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://erc-bpgc.github.io/blog/blog/mssr/</guid>
      <description>Robots were invented with the goal of helping humans carry out their tasks more comfortably, particularly 4D (Dirty, Dangerous, Difficult, and Dull) tasks. In designing robots, the conventional approach has been to design their hardware and software in accordance with the tasks they are supposed to do. Conventional robots can perform specific tasks accurately, but they are not very versatile and adaptive, and thus applications that are consigned to them rely heavily on their physical structure and controller capabilities.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
